[ Girl ] Swords and staves .
Tough road you got this year .
Judgement , Death ...
and Mr. Devil .
Glad it 's your birthday readin' and not mine .
Now here 's your card , Fool . See ?
That 's where I got your nickname . [ Fool ] Don 't remind me .
Here you go , 1 3 today . The golden-haired birthday boy ...
is settin 'off on life 's big adventure .
I ain 't no golden-haired nobody . And all I 'm only goin 'off to is seventh grade .
Well , you the Fool , and you can 't escape that . That ain 't bad .
No ? No . Ain 't the stupid kind of fool .
Only the ignorant kind , 'cause you 'rejust starting 'out .
Well , that 's better , I guess . Ah , but look here .
Already he 's got a problem , see ?
One step in front ? The drop off .
What about the dog ? That 's Fool 's companion .
See his spirit barking ?
Fool . ! Don 't go marching over that cliff , now .
Do the smart thing- - the high thing .
So what Fool gonna do ifhe ain 't gonna go off the cliff ? . Fly ?
He gonna do what he have to , Fool- -
turn around and walk the other way , right through the fire of the sun .
He get burned up ifhe do that .
Just the boy part get burned up .
Rest come out the other side a man ,
and no one calls him Fool again .
[ Coughing ]
[ Girl ] Just try to sleep , Mama . There 's nothing you can do .
Shh .
[ Coughing Continues ] Shh .
Just rest , Mom .
I don 't know what to do with this , Ruby .
I didn 't think the landlord would do this--not now .
Fool , you shouldn 't be here . Fool , go back to readin ' your book .
What 's wrong ? Nothin ' you can do . Go on .
[ Lighter Flicking ]
Who are you ?
Leroy , a friend of Ruby 's .
You the little brother she call Fool ?
[ Sighs ] My real name 's Poindexter ,
but Ruby hung up on them tarot cards .
Why Mama cryin ' ?
Y 'all been evicted . You gotta be out tomorrow midnight .
I guess Ruby didn 't see that one in the cards . But why ?
You 're three days late with your payment .
Fine print in the lease says you gotta pay triple else get out . Now , your mama and Ruby ain 't got triple .
Well , don 't the landlord know that- -
that Mama 's sick or Ruby got babies ?
Yeah , sure , he knows . He don 't care .
He wants to tear down the building . Y 'all the last family in it .
You got some money you can kick in ?
[ Distant Siren ]
I know a way you can earn some .
You game ?
[ Clearing Throat ]
One last family in the Lenox Avenue building ,
then it 's clear to tear down . [ Grunting ]
We build a nice , neat condominium . We get clean people in there .
Lots of nice wood for my fireplace . Lots of nice- - Money .
And money , mm-hmm . For me .
Mama , what happens to the people when you make them leave their home ?
I don 't believe I was speaking to you .
Speak when spoken to . That 's what good girls do .
You getting them out soon ? By tomorrow midnight .
Damn buckshot .
[ Chattering ]
[ Man ] Hey , Fool . ! Hey , I hear you 're gettin 'evicted , man . [ Coughing ]
[ Man # 2 ] Yeah , then yo 'ass goin 'be out on the street .
Hey , come back here . !
[ Chattering ]
- [ Man Shouts , Indistinct ] - [ Barking ]
[ Girl ] Hi , Fool .
[ Ruby ] He don 't need that kind of opportunity . He 's a good kid . Let 's keep it that way .
He work for me , he do better than the rest of ya . Out of seven , three 's already dead .
And then there 's you , baby- - turnin ' tricks on the strip .
Willy 's a crack addict , and what 's the other one 's name ? What 's he in jail for ? Assault ? Washington , and he didn 't do nothin ' .
He tried to put food on the damn table . That 's what I 'm tryin ' to teach the boy to do .
- He wants to be a doctor . - You can 't even afford to pay rent . !
- How the hell you gonna afford to send him to medical school ? - It ain 't right anyway .
Oh , that right ?
- You know your Mama got a cancer in her she can 't afford to have taken out ? - Leroy . !
- Yeah , the thing any doctor could take out just like that , but you ain 't got no money . ! - [ Muffled ]
And you ain 't gonna have no money unless- - Aah ! [ Kicks ]
You little snot- - Leroy , let go- -
Don 't touch me . Don 't touch me ! You listen up , you little punk .
Listen up ! Now , this is the big one , and somebody deserve to be robbed .
Somebody who don 't care nothin about families or about the neighborhood .
He just wanna bring the wrecking ' ball in so he can line his pockets .
Who you talkin ' about ?
The landlord , that 's who .
[ Siren Wailing ] The landlord of this building ? Yeah .
I found the treasure map last night in the back room of the liquor store me and Spenser hit- -
a letter addressed to the owner along with the name of his company .
So ? So the name of the company is the same as the name on your eviction notice .
Same guy who owns the liquor store owns this building and half the buildings in the ghetto .
I know where your landlord lives .
No . Leave him alone .
I heard things about him . Bad things .
You heard about the gold ?
This is from the company that wants to buy the coins the landlord collected- -
gold coins .
You wanna be stupid , Leroy ? You don 't need Fool for that .
We got a plan for him , baby- - " Fool " proof .
Or you want your family eating ' beans out in the street ?
One day I 'm gonna buy you a Cadillac for each foot , Mama ,
and you 're gonna skate around town looking so bad .
Just take care of the kids , Dexter .
You the man of the house now .
I 'm tryin ' , Mama .
I 'm tryin ' . [ Coughing ]
You didn 't lick this , did you ?
- No , ma 'am . - Stand up .
Hope this fits . I worked all day .
Turn around . Stand still .
[ Zipping ]
Do you love your mother ? Yes , ma 'am ?
" Yes , ma 'am , " what ?
Yes , ma 'am , I love you , Mother .
Good girl .
- Where 's your fork ? - Fork ?
I gave you a fork with this .
Where is your fork ?
Well , it must 've fallen- - somewhere on the floor maybe .
- You don 't know ? - No , I 'm sure it 's on the floor . I mean , I know I dropped it .
You know the punishment for losing silverware .
I 'm sure it 's right here . [ Moans Softly ]
I knew it was there .
Some niggers robbed the store . Again ?
May they burn in hell .
I 'm very tense from this .
You have one of your headaches ?
Ooh ! Very , very , tense about this .
Alice has been bad .
She 's been feeding that thing between the walls again .
- No . - [ Faint Wailing ]
Remember not to bruise her face .
Bad girls ... burn in hell .
[ Leroy ] There .
[ Man ] Jesus , it goes on forever .
No bars on the windows .
No car in the driveway . Maybe we lucked out . Where 's Fool ?
He 's goin ' in . Takin ' it cool .
[ Creaks ]
[ Thuds ]
[ Bell Rings ]
May I help you ?
Good afternoon , ma 'am . Sorry to bother you ,
but I 'd just like to show you some of these delicious cookies we 're selling .
I 'm sorry . We watch what we eat very carefully here .
I know it 's a bother , but so is cerebral palsy .
And if we don 't do all we can- - I 'm sorry .
Well , do you have , like , a bathroom I could use ? They leave us out here all day ...
without anywhere to take a leak . No . Sorry . No .
Sorry . Run along .
That 's all right . No . Run along .
That 's okay .
Heavy wire screens on the back windows .
They been hit before , you think ?
Uh , probably just the neighborhood .
How are the screens held on ? Padlocks on the outside .
Padlocks on the outside ? Geez . What else ? Any alarms ?
That I don 't know . She wouldn 't let me in . I told you to tell her you had to piss .
She wasn 't buying ' that .
I wanna take a look . Don 't be stupid , Spenser .
The kid told us all there was to see . We go in Sunday as we planned .
What if they got a remote alarm to the police ?
I 'm not goin ' in Sunday without checking ' out the security . Just look at the doors .
The basement . Maybe the connector boxes .
Now , how the hell are you gonna get in there ? She wouldn 't even let him up on the porch .
Well , you send a boy to do a man 's job , that 's what you get .
Anyway , you thought the Bear Scout disguise was good , watch this .
Help you ? Gas company , ma 'am .
Been an emergency .
Been an emergency . Need to check your meter . Passed it on your way up the drive .
Oh , that one we 've already got . There 's one inside the house that I need to check .
There 's none in the house . I 'm quite sure of that .
You 're probably not even aware of it , ma 'am , but it 's on the master list here , and I 'm gonna have to check it .
See , the situation is , we got leak on the block and it could be very dangerous .
- Identification ? - Oh , yeah .
Fact is , we do have the legal right to come in , even if we do have to call the police- -
not that we ever have .
It 's just there 've been an awful lot of robberies lately .
Neighborhood 's changing . Has us all a bit on edge .
I completely understand .
Better this little bother than a chance of danger , though , right ?
[ Fool ] I don 't know how he got past that woman . She 's got X-ray eyeballs .
[ Leroy ] Spenser 's as slippery as a snake . I think he 's up to somethin ' .
- Somethin ' like what ? - Like grabbing ' that coin collection for himself and cuttin ' me out .
Cuttin ' us out . Spenser mess with you , he gotta deal with me too .
[ Car Door Slams ] [ Chuckles ] You something ' , Fool .
[ Car Engine Starts ]
She leave him alone in the place ? You gotta be kiddin ;
Has to be someone else in there- - old folks , kids or somethin ' .
Maybe Spenser should stick his ugly head out and give us some kind of a signal .
Maybe he lookin ' around a little bit , make sure it 's safe .
Maybe the president is gonna make me secretary of pussy .
Now , he 's probably in there hiding ' the best for himself .
Come on . We goin ' in .
No . Spenser said we gotta stay out here , Leroy .
So he can get all the good shit for himself ?
Why not throw your mama out in the street along with Ruby and the kids ?
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Bell Rings ]
See ?
[ Crowbar Clinking ] [ Leroy Grunting ]
Uuh ! Fort Knox or what ?
Listen , Leroy . This breaking ' and enterin' might not be so smart .
I mean , it 's the first day of my 1 3th birthday .
Could be unlucky .
Thirteenth birthday is unlucky anyway .
Too old to get tit , too young to get ass . Fucked either way !
Lord , now , look at this .
The mother of all doors .
They ain 't messin ' around .
Spenser .
Spenser !
[ Creaking ]
Eh , so , Leroy ... you think I got what it takes to be a doctor ?
Doctor of burglary maybe . You 're lucky I 'm teachin ' you a trade , kid .
Ain 't no door stands up to Leroy .
I done busted this house 's cherry . It 's opened right up now .
[ Snarling ]
- Get back ! - Get off him !
- Get off ! . - [ Screaming ]
Hey , fuzzball ! Your mama sleeps with cats !
[ Grunting ]
Run , Fool !
That 's one mean motherfucker ! You see that ? He came at me like an airplane or somethin ' !
I saw him all right .
He gone ?
He 's waitin ' right there .
Been trained to wait there , probably .
He stay out there , and we stay right in here .
[ Insect Buzzing ]
[ Leroy ] This place is weird .
" See no evil , hear no evil , speak no evil . " [ Clears Throat ]
[ Leroy ] Every cabinet has a lock on it .
Why do you think they do that ?
Somebody need a bath bad .
[ Tapping ]
Heh ! Nice to see that rich folks got rats too .
Listen , Leroy . Let 's just get outta here -
out the front . Like , first , we find out what 's up with good old Spenser .
Man , the hell with Spenser ! Let 's just get outta here !
Hell with those gold coins , too , huh ?
Now , maybe you too stupid for this kind of work , or maybe you too chickenshit .
[ Thudding ]
Oh , there 's that bastard now .
He 's upstairs .
We 'll surprise him . Come on .
Comin 'or what ?
I 'm coming .
[ Clanking ]
[ Clock Tolling Hour ]
[ Gasps ]
I don 't think we should go up there , Leroy .
Oh , that 's fine , girlfriend .
I 'll tell you what . You stay down here , and you keep an eye out .
You think you can do that ? [ Kissing Sound ]
[ Chuckles ]
Yeah . I can do that .
Man , there 's enough room for 1 0 families in here .
[ Leroy ] Spenser . ! Spenser , you up here ?
[ Rumbling ]
[ Rattling ]
Spenser !
- Spenser , you back in there ? - [ Breathy Voice , Indistinct ]
I ain 't stupid .
" Or , maybe you just too chickenshit for this kind of work . "
[ Male Voice Muttering ]
[ Lock Clicks ] [ Ghostly Voice ] Fool . !
Spenser ?
[ Thud ]
Huh ! Spenser ?
[ Man ] How can you say that of me ? I 've never been unfaithful to you , ; never even looked at another woman .
[ Woman ] I 'm not talking about that at all .
[ Man , Woman Continue , Indistinct ]
[ Woman ] Ever since Sybil killed herself . Sybil 's death was- -
That 's what I am--a survivor . Tiffany . !
I 'm sorry , John , ; sorry for the both of us , ;
sorry for the child that ... we never had , and never will . !
Tiffany- - [ Continues , Indistinct ]
[ Clanging ]
[ Man On TV ] Oh , now , the antiaircraft battery !
They 're firing . It 's weird .
The barracks . They 're over by the barracks . [ Continues , Indistinct ]
And now , here it comes . Baghdad is lighting up !
Tracers flaring up like angry hornets from every rooftop now .
We cannot see see bombers , but the fire of their munitions is shaking the city .
It 's shaking our hotel .
There 's a- - Where ? Do you see it ?
There ! Right over there ! It 's flying just over the rooftops !
Spenser , you back in there ? Aah !
[ Man Laughing ]
[ Indistinct Shout ] Aah !
[ Grunting ]
Spenser .
[ Grunting Continues ]
You can 't do that , you miserable , stinkin ' thief ! .
[ Gibberish ]
Come on , Spens . I 'm gonna get you outta here .
Man . This ain 't right .
Who are you ?
[ Shouting , Screaming ]
Leroy , we gotta get out of this place ! Oh , no !
Whoa !
- Uuh ! - [ Grunting , Moaning ]
Ohh !
Let me go ! Uuh !
[ Panting ]
Hello ? Miss ?
[ Vehicle Rumbles ]
[ Barking ]
Leroy ! Leroy !
Leroy ?
- Leroy ! - Jesus !
- Yaah ! - You scared the shit out of me !
I thought you were dead , Leroy . You was just layin ' there .
A man ain 't dead just ' cause he 's layin ' on the floor .
I was listenin ' . Somethin 's in there .
As a matter of fact , why don 't you crawl in there and see what it is ?
You turkey brain ! You hittin ' on me , and I come up here to save your ass !
Your gonna stick your dumb head in there and lose it just like Spenser !
- What kind of shit you talkin ' ? - I 'm talkin ' we gotta get out of here , Leroy !
That X-ray lady 's back . She 's out back right now by the van .
She got a man with her the size of Detroit . !
- Damn . You seen Spenser ? - I seen Spenser all right .
- He find anything ? - Somethin ' found him .
He 's dead , Leroy- - I think scared to death .
You sure ?
[ Scoffs ] You thought he was white before ? You should see that sucker now !
[ Door Opens , Shuts ]
- [ Man ] There is somebody in there . The doors have been pried open . - I told you there 'd be another one .
Out the front . Uh-oh !
[ Crackling ] Wow ! Uuh !
Oh , shit .
Oh , my hand .
[ Fool Groaning ]
[ Woman ] Pry it open at the bottom- - enough so Prince can get in .
[ Snarling , Barking ]
Oh , God .
Come on , Fool ! Aah ! What are you doing ? Aah !
Stand right here , right in the open , so the fuckin ' dog can see you .
You think I 'm crazy ? That mother got teeth he ain 't even used yet !
Do like I say , or I 'm gonna take your head off .
I 'm gonna nail that sucker . Don 't worry . I 'm worried .
[ Man Growls ] Kill . ! Get ' em . !
Uh , uh-oh .
[ Whispers ] Where 'd he go ?
[ Growls ]
Shit ! Shit ! [ Screams ]
Get the fuck off me ! Aah !
- Pull , Leroy ! - Fool ! What the hell you doin ' , Fool ?
Come on ! Come on !
Fool ! Come on !
Aah ! [ Indistinct Shout ]
[ Pained Yelling ]
I 'm gonna take your fuckin ' head off ! .
[ Both Blathering ]
[ Both Groaning ]
[ Woman ] I heard ' em yell . ! I heard ' em go down . !
[ Prince Growling ]
I told you , don 't mess with me .
Man , I saved your life . Are these people crazy or what ? You ask ' em !
Get in there , Daddy . ! Get in there and get ' em . ! Clear it out . ! Make it safe for Mommy .
[ Grunting ]
[ Banging ]
Ow ! Damn !
[ Woman ] Little doggy baby . Someone is in here .
People under the stairs got the so-called gas man .
Other one must be upstairs .
Princey ! Daddy 'll get ' em .
That 's a big caliber automatic . You ever see the holes they tear ?
We can hide under the bed . No , I ain 't goin ' in there , man . There 's somethin ' about that place .
No room . Find your own .
[ Distant Yelping ]
Ehh ! Aah !
[ Man Grunting ]
Aha . !
Oh !
Aah . ! Run , Fool . !
Uuh !
Whoo . Yee-haw !
Got him ! [ Laughing ] [ Whooping ]
Oh , Daddy !
Did you see that ? Yeah . !
He came at me like a bull . Just like a bull .
Big one !
Hear what he called me ? He called you a fool .
He 's the fool . ! Only good fool 's a dead one .
Yeah . ! [ Laughing ]
Ooh , better check upstairs . Might be a mess .
Oh , no . Don 't want a mess . I better go look .
Might have to mop up a little .
Thought I heard somethin ' . Stay there .
Get back in the cellar , you little bastard !
You little animal shit !
I 'll get the dog up here . You 'll be sorry .
My- - My name is Fool .
What 's yours ? Alice .
Don 't be scared . You never seen a brother before ?
- Never had a brother . - No , I mean a black dude .
There 's black folks in this neighborhood . Neighborhood ?
[ Prince Barking ] A neighborhood .
You know- - outside ?
Well , that 's outside , not in here .
So , you get outside , don 't you ?
- You sayin ' never ? - Can 't get out . No one ever has .
Well- - Well , I 'm gonna get out .
I 'm a whole other thing .
People have tried .
Y- - You mean the people in the cellar ?
Mm , who are they ?
Mommy and Daddy looked a long time to find the perfect boy child ,
but each one they found turned out bad .
Some saw things they weren 't supposed to .
Others heard too much . Others talked back .
Daddy cut out the bad parts and put the boys in the cellar ...
one by one .
They get flashlights and food of some kind .
I suppose they 're happy in their own way .
Yeah , right .
What about you ?
How come they haven 't put you in the cellar ?
I do not see ...
or hear ... or speak evil .
It 's the only way .
[ Thud ] [ Wailing , Moaning ]
- What is that ? - What ?
- That yelling ' . What is that ? - Well , that 's Roach .
Roach ? That 's who Daddy 's hunting .
See , Daddy hates Roach ' cause he got out of the cellar and into the walls ,
and now Daddy can 't find him .
[ Wailing Continues ]
Fire !
There must be another way out .
Further into the house- - the only way . Here .
Papa 's too big to follow , and he 's afraid of what 's in there .
- I don 't want in . I want out . - Sometimes in is out .
[ Roach Wails ]
Forget it .
- Haah ! - [ Roach Cackling ]
I hear ya . ! I hear ya . ! [ Gunshot ]
Aha !
Yes . Aha .
Okay . I 'll get in there .
[ Gunshot ]
[ Thud ] [ Roach Cackling ]
Ah ! Yeah ? Aah ! Hah !
Yeah . ! Ha ha . ! I 'm gonna get ya . !
Oh . ! [ Gunshot ]
Yes ! [ Cackling Continues ]
[ Grunting ]
I got something for my Princey . Yes . Come on .
Come on . Come on .
Good appetite . Healthy Prince ,
a secure home .
[ Brakes Screech ]
Stay .
[ Woman On Police Radio ] We have a registration that matches a description of a van ...
used in a 21 1 last night .
[ Gunshots Continue ]
[ Echoing , Feedback ] Daddy , police out back .
Damn !
- [ Yelps ] - [ Growls ]
Hey , police ! Police !
[ Police Radio ] 5 1 4 respond , 2 1 1 . [ No Audible Dialogue ]
Police ! Police !
Hello . What can I do for you gentlemen ?
Afternoon , ma 'am . Uh , is this your van ?
Uh , goodness , no . It was just standing here when we got back from shopping .
You see anybody around when you pulled in ? Trouble ?
Well , as a matter of fact we did see a couple of men- - one black , one white- -
walking away as we approached .
We thought they were service people of some sort .
- You know they 're workin on your door , don 't ya ? - No harm done .
Ah , we 'll check the house . Just checked it . Even looked under the beds .
Clean as a whistle . Well , let 's recon the neighborhood . There 's still a chance .
- You get a lot of this sort of thing ? - It 's as if we 're the prisoners , and the criminals roam free .
I know what you mean . You 're lucky you 're all right . This van was used in a liquor-store robbery last night .
Well , goodness .
- Liquor store ? - I 'd advise you to stay inside , keep your doors locked for a while .
You can count on it .
Hope you catch ' em .
- Catch ' em in hell . - Oh , my God .
What ? There 's not just the two .
There 's a boy .
[ Sniffs ] He 's in there right now ...
with our little angel .
[ Snarling ]
God , what are they feeding ' you ?
[ Belches ]
- [ Fool Yelps ] - [ Prince Whines ]
[ Man ] What is it , boy ?
Huh ?
[ Gunshots ]
Huh ? Uuh !
Oww !
Son of a bitch . ! Oh . ! Oh . !
You come in here , and I 'm gonna kick your ass !
Aah ! Come on !
Gonna kill you !
Uuh ! Aah !
[ Cackling ]
Kill . Git .
Ki-i-ill !
- [ Yelping ] - [ Snarling ]
Go !
This your place ? [ Yelping ]
Aa-aa-aah !
What hit you ? The damn Bear Trooper .
Prince is after him .
He 'll kill him before he gets to Alice .
Let 's do something !
[ Cackling ]
Do you hear something ?
The boy 's gotten to Alice .
- Thanks . - [ Laughs ]
He doesn 't talk much , does he ?
H-His tongue 's cut out .
Oh , man .
Mommy caught him trying to call for help one day , and Daddy had to teach him- -
Speak no evil , right ?
Your father 's one sick mother , you know that ?
Actually , your mother 's one sick mother too .
Shh ! [ Whispers ] You 're speaking evil .
They 'd kill you if they heard a word you just said .
Roach- - Roach is my friend .
Roach ? I 'm Poindexter .
[ Mutters ] Everybody calls me Fool .
Fool ?
We sure got the names , huh ?
[ Laughs ]
This Leroy ?
You did this ? Why you make these ?
To hold the souls ofburglars when they died .
Or salesmen , workmen- -
other people who saw too much .
[ Indistinct Shout ]
Uuh !
[ Indistinct Shouts ]
- You viper in my bosom ! You littleJudas ! - What do I do with him , Mommy ?
It is time to clean house .
Total spring cleaning .
Hey , let 's move it . !
Oh , you little piece of shit !
No , wait a minute- - Aah ! Aah ! Aah !
[ Woman ] I am sick and tired of your attitude . !
You will do your chore now !
Clean it up , for God 's sake !
What 's a mother to do ? Lazy brat sits in her room all day ...
sewing dolls !
Children misbehaving in the basement !
And one in the wall ...
doing his business God knows where .
You kids 'll be the death of me . !
[ Whispering ] The death of me .
[ People Chattering , Shouting ]
[ Shouting ]
I keep ' em real hungry .
I ask a simple thing .
Just clean up that awful man 's blood .
And what do you do ? You get it all over your nice , clean dress ...
I worked so hard to make !
Now , get in that tub and scrub yourself ! .
No ! [ Wailing ]
Don 't want to get in , huh ?
Well , let me help you !
You 're gonna scrub yourself ! . You scrub yourself ! .
It 's hot , but the fires of hell are hotter .
No ! Don 't put me in there !
Don 't put- - No !
No ! [ Whimpering ]
No ! Don 't put me in there !
Where 's the Bear Trooper ?
Dead meat .
I coulda killed him ,
but I 'll let the people under the stairs do it .
Leave me alone !
Get away from me !
[ Moaning ]
[ All Gasping ]
[ Moaning Continues ]
Roach !
It 's right there , Roach .
[ Man ] I told you to keep it quiet down there .
You 're driving me nuts . Pull it .
Guard ' em , Prince . Guard ' em .
[ Men Gasping ]
Noisy bastards .
If I have to come down there , you 're gonna be sorry .
Roach , you 're shot . We got to get you to a hospital .
[ Barking ]
It 's a coin collection . Leroy was right .
Thanks , Roach .
[ Whimpering ]
Alice is up there ?
Roach !
[ Whispers ] Roach .
[ Prince Barking , Snarling ]
[ Barking ]
[ Gasps ] Get out of here !
Go !
[ Man ] What did he do to you ? I told you- -
Hear me ? Come here . You answer me . !
Did you tell him anything ?
If you did , you know what I 'll do .
I killed your skinny friend in the walls .
Now , what do you think of that ?
Oh , and I got him good .
And the black one too .
[ Gasping ]
Shut the fuck up !
[ Shuddering ] What the hell 's wrong with him ?
He said he killed you ! He exaggerated !
Come on ! Stay .
Keep moving , Alice . He finds us , he gonna shoot through the walls .
My dress is stuck on something .
Oh , great .
Uh-oh . We got to keep going , Alice . Come on .
Burn in hell for gettin ' free ,
and burn in hell for showin ' the way !
Who turned on the heat ?
[ Chuckling ]
Burn ! Burn !
Burn in hell !
Burn !
Burn in hell . !
Burn in hell .
[ Coughing ]
Alice , he 's comin ' closer . We got to get out of here .
[ Coughing ] Which way ?
Only Roach knew the way through the walls .
So we 'll explore .
[ Man ] Gonna find you . !
I gotta sneeze ! Gonna kill ya . !
[ Sneezes ]
[ Alice ] Shh ! If he can 't hear us , he can 't shoot us .
[ Both Gasp ]
We got to be careful . Real careful .
- You think you got him ? - We 'll soon find out .
Come on , Prince . Come on , boy . Come on . Kill . Kill . Kill .
[ Snarls ] Kill . Kill ' em , Prince .
Kill ' em . Kill ' em !
Shh ! I think I just heard something .
- [ Snarling ] - Oh ! Come on !
- [ Fool ] I 'm not runnin 'anymore . - [ Prince Snarling ]
Come on !
[ Chuckling ]
[ Alice ] Fool ?
Alice !
Alice , get back !
[ Alice ] Get away from the wall . ! Get away from the wall . !
[ Fool Moaning ]
Gotcha .
Gotcha !
Jesus .
I got him ! I got him ! I got him , I got him !
I got him . I got him . I got him , I got him , I got him .
Got him , I got him . I got him , I got him , I got him .
Prove it .
Hey , hey , wait a minute .
It 's light up there . Come on .
I know you 're in there , you little piece of shit .
- [ Snarling ] - [ Woman Gasps ]
[ Body Thuds ]
Oh , shit . You killed Prince !
[ Man , Woman Arguing ]
[ Fool ] Look . You can see the lights of the ghetto from here .
I never thought smog could smell so good .
- Help ! - Shh !
We might have to climb down . There 's nothing to hold on to .
It 's just a straight drop off the roof .
Wait a minute . What ?
The water in the garden .
Think it 's right under this window . If wejump off the edge , we might be able to hit it .
- I don 't know how deep it is . - [ Man Knocking ] I hear ' em .
Alice , come on . We got to jump .
- I can 't . I 'm afraid . - [ Man Shouting , Indistinct ]
- Alice ! - What 's out there ?
- [ Grunts ] - [ Gasps ] - There he is . !
Ah !
[ Alice Whimpering ]
What were you doing with him ? Come here .
Alice ! Alice !
[ Gasps ]
Oh , no , no , no , no , no !
[ Shouting ]
Damn it .
[ Fool Gasps ] [ Gun Cocks ]
I 'll be back , Alice ! Hang on !
- Bastard ! - I 'll be back . !
Never shoot your gun outside .
- He got away . - Come back inside .
Damn it .
Bad boy ! Go on .
Go straight to your room and get into your suit .
If these had come from anybody else , I 'd tan your hide and make you take ' em straight back .
You know that ? Yes , sir .
Well , figuring the rarity of these ,
you do have enough to pay your rent for a while .
Say , to the year 2000 .
- Hey , and Mama 's operation ? - And your mama 's operation .
Keep hold of these till tomorrow .
I 'm gonna order an ambulance for your mama .
Tomorrow we 'll take those to a good coin dealer ,
and we 'll all be smiling .
Meanwhile , you be careful .
That brother / sister act you messed with are evil , plain and simple .
- Wait a minute . Brother and sister ? - Brother and sister .
Tail end of the craziest family you ever heard of .
Every generation more insane than the one before it .
Started out as a family running a funeral home .
Sellin ' cheap coffins for expensive prices .
Then they got their fingers into real estate ,
started making a lot of money taking over people 's homes .
The more money they got , the greedier they got .
The greedier they got , the crazier they got .
All sorts of rumors about what 's gone on in that place .
Never proved it because the police didn 't take it serious .
But believe me , when I was a kid , none of us ever walked past that house .
You okay , Fool ?
I was just telling Mama that I did something wrong .
Real wrong . And now I gotta do something right .
I done the tarot cards on you again .
They come up real scary . Don 't go messin ' with them people again .
Somebody has to . And maybe that means me .
Anyway , I made a promise to Alice ,
and I 'm gonna keep it . [ Door Closes ]
[ Woman ] 1 4th Precinct . Hello . Police ?
Yes . This is the police . I 'd like to report a case of child abuse goin ' on .
All right . When did this happen ? Right now .
This real or what ? Bogus .
This place is clean . People don 't even have kids .
Got coffee though .
More coffee ? No , thank you . Had plenty .
I 'm so sorry you all had to come out at such an hour ...
for such a silly thing .
But you know , it 's better there are a few false calls ...
if we can prevent just one child from being abused .
Mm-hmm . Absolutely right . Cream and sugar ?
Nice furniture . You didn 't get that stuff at Price Club , that 's for sure .
You know , it 's been in the family for years . Yeah ?
It used to be , the house was used for , uh ,
business . No kiddin ' ?
Sergeant , I think there 's something here you might want to see .
What ? Take a look .
- Thought you said you had no kids . - Alice left us a long time ago , Sergeant .
The Lord saw fit to come and take her .
Never touched the room since .
We 're foolish , I suppose , but ...
in a sense , she still lives here .
And always will . My apologies .
It must be very painful for you .
I 'm sorry about this . It should have never happened .
No need to apologize . We want to be helpful .
[ Policeman ] Thanks for the refreshments . [ Man ] You 're welcome .
Good night . I don 't want to see another cop ...
or cookie in my life .
I don 't know which one makes me sicker .
May they burn in hell .
Forever and ever in hell .
The shelf worked . Yep . Always does .
Simple works best .
We got to get a new dog tomorrow .
A good , big one .
I was worried . The police left the back door open for so long .
So ? I couldn 't watch it all the time .
Think any of 'em got out ? Nah .
They were pretty out of it . What 'd you use ?
Horse tranquilizers .
[ Man ] Tomorrow I 'm gonna look for the Bear Trooper .
[ Woman ] Where would you look ? The ghetto .
I 'll find him . And I 'll kill him .
Night , Mama . Night , Daddy .
Say your prayers like a good boy ? Oh . I forgot .
[ Woman ] Now I lay me down to sleep .
[ Man ] Now I lay me down to sleep .
[ Together ] I pray the Lord my soul to keep .
If I should kill before I wake ,
[ Woman ] I pray the Lord my soul to take .
[ Man ] I pray the Lord my soul to take .
[ Screams ] You miserable little shit !
Shut up ! [ Screaming ]
Get him ! You hurt my baby !
[ Screaming ]
[ Woman ] Get him ! Get him !
[ Man , Woman Screaming ]
Get him ! He 's getting away ! [ Screaming Continues ]
Downstairs door .
[ Woman ] You get him ? He 's fast , damn it .
Open the kitchen !
[ Groaning ] Shit !
What happened ? Did he get out ?
Burn in hell . Burn in hell .
[ Woman ] What about Alice ? What 'll we do with her ?
[ Man ] Let her hang up there all night .
[ Woman ] She 's terrified of the attic . I know .
It serves her right .
Alice . Fool ?
Are you okay ?
Alice , can you get any more of these bricks out ?
- I can 't . They 've got me stuck . - How ?
I 'm tied to a bolt in the chimney .
This one ?
Oh , yes .
Hi . Hi .
Let 's see if we can get some more of these bricks out .
Shh !
Get down .
Let me down , please .
[ Exhales Forcefully ] Daddy !
Come down from there and help me to bed . !
Daddy !
I said now . !
[ Lock Clicks ] He 's gone .
Fool ? Fool ?
Meet me at the window . You know the one . Okay .
You find him , bring him back to me . I will .
Take him under the stairs and do him like the others . I 'll kill him .
- Only it won 't be his ears I cut off . - His balls . !
Here , hold this .
Listen , Alice . They 're not your real parents .
What ? They 're not . They 're not even husband and wife .
They stole you , like they did Roach and all the others .
They 're a bunch of rotten baby snatchers .
You-You 're just saying that .
My Grandfather Booker told me , and he wouldn 't lie to me .
What do we do now ?
- Feel up to a little jump ? - Problem is ,
first thing he did when you escaped was drain it ...
and put broken glass and rocks in the bottom .
- That 's a problem . - The way we came up before he 's got fixed now .
Wait , Fool ! Look !
[ Fool ] This place is one big bomb .
[ Alice ] He 's got ' em all over the house .
Think you could climb the roof ?
What 's up there ?
The only way out .
[ Woman ] How dare he come in to our happy home ?
He came back to get Alice . You should have let me kill her .
You stay away from Alice ! She did it with him ! I know it !
Not my little girl ! She 's a whore !
[ Clattering ]
What is that ?
- [ Shot Fires ] - [ Alice ] Oh , God . !
It hurts so bad . ! [ Laughing ]
[ Shot Fires ] See him ?
I can 't see shit .
Let me see the brick .
Hold it . I think I hear something .
- Bombs away . - No !
[ Thud ] [ Groaning ]
- [ Woman ] That little bastard ! - This here 's one of your smart bricks .
- You bastard ! - Come on . You can do it .
Just watch yourself on the sides .
[ Groaning Continues ]
Oh , shit . Hang on .
You 're mine now !
[ Screaming ]
Caca . !
Okay , hold it here . Why ?
You know where we are ? Huh-uh .
There 's the living room . Get out the back door .
Well , come with me then . I 'm not finished with them yet .
- Fool- - - Go !
I 'm goin 'to get the shotgun , set those kids free .
[ Voice Murmuring , Faint ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Murmuring Continues ]
Fool ! Fool !
Shh !
Hold it right there ! [ Gasping ]
Where is that little bastard ? Tell me !
Tell me ! I-I won 't tell you .
We will get him out of our house ! He 's filthy .
He 's bad . He 's awful !
[ Screams ]
Go to hell !
[ Man ] Mommy . ! Oh . !
[ Woman ] Eldon . ! Oh , God .
He 's turned my little girl against me .
I told you . Those two- -
Then she can burn in hell .
Both of them .
She doesn 't have a key . She 's still in here .
[ Voices Murmuring , Shouting ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Glass Shattering ] [ Objects Clattering ]
She 's in the cellar . No way .
Then he is .
You know a prayer ?
Say it .
Whoa !
Shoot her if you see her .
[ Man Chuckling ]
Come here !
[ All Shouting ]
- You see your friends ? - [ Flies Buzzing ]
- Get him ? - Oh , yeah .
[ Knocking ] Shh !
It may be the police again . Hold on .
My name is Ruby Williams , and I represent the Association of People Who Have Been ...
Unjustly Evicted , Exploited and Generally Fucked Over . What ?
You and your brother are landlords of over 50 buildings in this city ...
all of which you 've allowed to deteriorate into rat-infested hell holes ...
while you get rich charging ridiculous rents .
Then you evict anyone the minute they can 't pay rent ,
so you can tear down their home and build more office buildings .
- Ain 't that about right ? - None of your goddamn business !
Kill the little bugger !
Kiss your ass good-bye , boy .
[ People Shouting ]
[ All Shouting ]
- What the hell is going on ? - He 's loose again ! Damn it .
- [ Knocking ] - [ Man ] Police . ! Open up . !
- Shh ! - What ?
[ Man ] Police . ! We have reports of gunfire . !
If you do not open this door , we 'll break it down . !
Get off my property . ! Just wanna finish saying our piece , ma 'am .
Not only are you bad landlords , but 1 0 times worse ,
you 've stolen the children from our community for your own sick needs .
There is no community here .
All I see are a couple of n- -
[ Man ] Hey , Ruby , we 're right here . [ Woman ] You got that right .
Busted your ass , bitch . Yeah .
What are you gonna do ? Shoot us all ?
- You 'll do . - [ Crashing ]
[ Ruby ] Damn . You knocked that bitch cold . !
[ Man ] Man , look at her . What are they doin 'to her in there ?
[ People Shouting ]
Oh , shit .
I know you 're in here .
You 're not gettin ' out .
Nobody gets out .
[ Gun Cocks ] Nobody .
Fool ?
[ Ruby ] Fool , that you ?
[ Shouting ]
Listen , there 's a way out for you guys if you can get past the man .
Huh ?
The door to the outside cellar got left open .
Now you can get outside- - to the sun ,
to the birds , to the women .
You want to give me something ?
[ Gasping ] Shh !
Burglar alarm ? No problem . I studied with the best .
I can use these wires to bridge it .
[ People Shouting ]
No wonder there 's no money in the ghetto .
Fool ?
Fool ! Fool !
[ Door Shuts , Lock Clicks ]
[ Ruby ] Uh-oh . Your mama 's gone .
Oh , shit . Where did that crazy heifer go ?
You guys see where she went ? Don 't let her get away , hear ?
- Wait a minute . ! Let us help you . ! - [ Knocking ]
Please , open the door !
We want to help you !
Open the door . !
[ Male Computer Voice ] System remote override . All doors locked .
[ Woman ] You know I wouldn 't let you get away that easy .
I see you .
And I see you , dearie .
[ Screaming ]
[ Shouting ]
[ Biting ]
You get back in there ! Get back in there !
Don 't you touch me !
Don 't you touch me ! No !
[ Shouting ]
[ Flesh Tearing ]
[ Gasping , Sobbing ]
[ Growls ]
You hurt your mother .
You 're not my mother .
Never were .
Then burn in hell !
[ Woman Screaming ] [ People Shouting ]
Mommy !
[ All Chuckling ]
[ Coins Clattering ]
[ Man ] Oh , no . No , no . Fool . !
[ People Shouting " Fool " ]
[ Coin Clatters ]
[ Clattering Continues ]
I know what you 're doing . You 're counting that money .
You 're letting it roll through your fingers .
I 've done it myself ...
a thousand times .
And I 'll do it again . But you won 't !
- Hey . - [ Gasps ]
You shoot me and you die , too , man .
And you better believe it .
Don 't be crazy , now .
Got enough dynamite down there to blow you sky-high .
Not the best place to store it , in my opinion .
But there it was . Just put the gun down .
Put the gun down .
I don 't want to kill you , but I will , 'cause I don 't like you much anyway .
I 'm tired of fuckin ' around ! So either put the gun down now ...
or kiss your ass good-bye , boy .
- [ Shouting ] - [ Gasps ]
Holy shit !
[ People Cheering ]
[ Cheering Continues ] [ Groaning ]
All right .
[ All Clamoring ]
Fool ?
Fool , you okay ?
I feel like a million dollars .
[ People Whistling , Cheering ]
# Do the right thing I 'm not talking about a black or white thing #
# ' Cause that would cause conflict and make this illegit #
# But your definition oflegit and illegitimate is confusing #
# I wanna say #
# To make things clearer present about a year or two #
# What you do is take a look upon the mirror #
# And what you see is the image ofhate #
# That you shed upon my sisters and my brothers #
# Now , in my opinion you need some education #
# The whole world is actin like a giant aggravation #
# I asked my man Victor what he used to do before #
# And he said he learned to shoot a gun before the age of 2 1 #
# Crime and abortion are kinds of my distortion #
# This is very important butjust a word of caution #
# What you can do here 's a clue and it 's true #
# Yo , [ Indistinct ] and make your life better #
# And do the right thing # # Do the right thing #
# You got to do the right thing # # Do the right thing #
# Do the right thing # # Do the right thing #
# You got to do the right thing # # Do the right thing , yeah #
# # [ Rap Continues , Indistinct ]
# The same way she loved you you loved her right back #
# But now you picked a bone and you argue a lot #
# Over money I got from dealing 'stuff on the block #
# And do the right thing # # Do the right thing #
# You got to do the right thing # # Do the right thing #
# Do the right thing # # Do the right thing #
# You got to do the right thing # # Do the right thing , yeah #
# You 're not the only one in the world that has problems #
# Keep your head straight and you can slowly solve them #
# Be a fly guy and reach sky-high #
# And like theJeffersons you get a piece of the pie #
# I hope you take heed to the message I brought #
# In other words the lesson I taught #
# The Red 'll kick a lyric but I won 't sing #
# And the F.B.I. crew wants you and you to do the right thing #
# Do the right thing #
# You got to do the right thing # # Do the right thing #
# Do the right thing # # Do the right thing #
# You got to do the right thing # # Do the right thing , yeah #
# We count it off as we go A little something like this #
# One two , three Manhattan , you gotta do the right thing #
# Brooklyn , you gotta do the right thing #
# And the Bronx you gotta do the right thing #
# Queens Island You gotta do the right thing #
# Long Island you gotta do the right thing #
# Staten Island you gotta do the right thing #
# On the West Coast you gotta do the right thing #
# Everybody , everybody in the world you gotta do the right thing #
# Do the right thing #
# Do the right thing # # Do the right thing #
# You got to do the right thing # # Do the right thing #
# You got to do the right thing # # Do the right thing , yeah #
# Redhead one sending 'out a message on a positive note #
# Try to make you all see the light when we supposed to be in the dark #
# Yo , this is goin 'out to my mother , to my brother #
# To the rest of the F.B.I. tribe you know what I 'm sayin ' #
# Everybody else in the world I just want y 'all to do one thing #
# And that 's the right thing # # Do the right thing #
# You got to do the right thing # # Do the right thing #
# Do the right thing # # Do the right thing #
# You got to do the right thing # # Do the right thing , yeah #
# The right thing # # Do the right thing #
# Do the right thing # # Do the right thing #